<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- REP for repetitions or repeated phrases close to eachother
     META for metaphors
     SIM for similes
     SELF for phrases by the author to the author (probably)
     TIME for relating to time
-->
<root><title>Leaves</title>
    <author>Lloyd Schwartz</author> - <year>1941</year>- <page>1</page>
    <stanza>Every <time>October</time> it becomes important, <self>no, <i>necessary</i></self> to
        see the <rep>leaves turning, to be surrounded by leaves turning</rep>; it's not just the
        symbolism, <rep>to confront in the death of the year your death</rep>, one blazing farewell
        appearance, though the irony isn't lost on you that nature is most seductive when it's about
        to die, flaunting the dazzle of its incipient exit, an ending that at least so far the
        effects of human progress (pollution, acid rain) have not yet frightened you enough to make
        you believe is real; that is, you know this ending is a deception because of course nature
        is always renewing itself— the trees don't <i>die</i>, they just pretend, <rep>go out in
            style, and return in style: a new style.</rep></stanza>
    <page>2</page>
    <stanza>Is it deliberate how far they make you go especially if you live in the city to get far
        enough away from home to see not just trees but only trees? The boring highways, roadsigns,
        high speeds, 10-axle trucks passing you as if they were in an even <time>greater
            hurry</time> than you to look at leaves: so you drive in terror for literal
            <time>hours</time> and it looks like rain, or <i>snow</i>, but it's probably just clouds
            <self>(too cloudy to see any color?)</self> and you wonder, given the poverty of your
        memory, which road had the most color <time>last year</time>, but it doesn't matter since
        you're probably too <time>late</time> anyway, or too <time>early</time>— whichever road you
        take will be the wrong one and you've probably come all this way for nothing.</stanza>
    <page>3</page>
    <stanza>You'll be driving along depressed when suddenly a cloud will move and the sun will
        muscle through and ignite the hills. <rep>It may not last. Probably won't last.</rep> But
        for a <time>moment</time> the whole world comes to. Wakes up. <rep>Proves it lives. It
            lives—</rep>
        <i>red, yellow, orange, brown, russet, ocher, vermilion, gold</i>. <rep>Flame and rust.
            Flame and rust</rep>, the permutations of burning. <rep><meta>You're on fire.</meta>
            <meta>Your eyes are on fire.</meta></rep>
        <rep>It won't last, you don't want it to last.</rep> You can't stand any more. But you don't
        want it to stop. <rep>It's what you've come for. It's what you'll come back for.</rep>
        <rep>It won't stay with you, but <sim>you'll remember that it felt like nothing else you've
                felt or something you've felt that also didn't last</sim>.</rep></stanza></root>
